

CONTCT DETAILS

- Mobile: +91- 9845734653
- B
- Mail: <u>Unixsearch@gmail.com</u>
- Skype Id: chand275636
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ch and-pasha-6547616b/

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

M.C. A Master's in
Computer Applications passed out
in 2009 from Osmania University

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Information Technologies
 Infrastructure Library ITIL V3
 Certified.
- o Six Sigma trained at HCLCommNet Systems & ServicesLtd.
- Red hat Certified System
 Administrator (RHCSA) Exam
 (EX200).
- Azure Administrator 104Associate Professional

LANGUAGES -



Hindi

Urdu

INTEREST









Chand Pasha

Sr. Consultant @Hitachi

PROFILE -

To achieve the best in my career and to work with a team of intelligent and active personalities, which helps me improve my career and to learn new things and meet the requirement of the Organization. The primary responsibility is to support the existing and implement new Cloud and Linux/Unix Infrastructure. Equally good in both the technologies implementing, deploying, and maintaining enterprise level, distributed systems using cloud services like Azure, Amazon AWS, Oracle Cloud Infrastructure, On-Premises Cloud Infrastructure and Data centre experience.

Experience -

MAR 2020 -

Till Date

Sr. Consultant

11+ years of experience in multiple Clouds (Azure, OCI, AWS, Rancher, OpenStack) along applications with heterogeneous environments for Cloud, UNIX/Linux servers and workstations running with DevOps tools, Cloud infrastructure and Cloud services. Currently working with Hitachi Consulting Pvt Ltd (Hitachi Vantara), Hyderabad

Cloud Solutions Architect

Mar 2019 –

JAN 2020

NOV 2013 – APR 2019 Worked as a **Cloud Solutions Architect** with **Sunera Technologies Pvt Ltd**, **Hyderabad**.

Solaris Administrator

Worked as a **Solaris Administrator** with **First Advantage Global Operating Centre**, **Bangalore**.

Nov 2011 –

Nov 2013

Technical Specialist

Worked as a **Technical Specialist** with **HCL Commnet System & Services Ltd, Bangalore**.

NOV 2010 – APR - 2011 **Senior Specialist**

Worked as a **Senior Specialist** with **HCL Commnet System & Services Ltd, Chennai.**

CORE COMPETENCIES-

Rancher Cloud, AWS, OCI, Azure

Red hat, Centos, OEL and Solaris

Dockers, Jenkins, Spacewalk, Git

Apache, tomcat

IBM Blade chassis, Oracle, HP and Dell

VMware, Oracle Virtual Box

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY 5:

Working as a **Sr. Consultant** at **Hitachi Consulting (Hitachi Vantara) at Financial District Gachibowli** from Mar 2020 to till date, www.hitachi.com

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure:

- Define and monitor the security and privacy aspects of the cloud.
- Regularly evaluate cloud applications, hardware, and software.
- Respond to technical issues in a professional and timely manner.
- ➤ Identify the top cloud architecture solutions to successfully meet the strategic needs of the company.
- Storage allocation, reclaims, backups and restores on cloud.
- > Infrastructure CI/CD pipeline automation and related systems Jenkins.
- > Active Directory Integration with Hitachi Custom tools like HID and Groundwork.
- Patch Assessment for Unix and Linux systems.
- Accomplish monthly and Quarterly audit for clients for customers.
- Implement security bug fixes for all the Unix/Linux systems.
- ➤ Build & migrate the Unix / Linux systems on to Oracle Cloud.
- Build & migrate the Custom Monitoring for Oracle and cloud services through Groundwork Monitoring.
- > Implement Error, Correlation, Categorisation, and alert configuration rules on ECM tool.
- > Install Splunk forwarder, Configure Security App, and Indexer.
- > Publishing internal technical documents and mentoring the new hires.
- POC on Azure cloud for upcoming projects.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY 4:

Worked as a **Cloud Solutions Architect at SUNERA Technologies PVT LTD**. **Hyderabad** from Mar 2019 to Jan 2020, <u>www.suneratech.com</u>

Description: (Meritor Inc, run with the bull)

Headquartered in Troy, Michigan. Meritor is a leading global supplier of drive train, mobility, braking and aftermarket solutions for commercial vehicle and industrial markets. With years of experience engineering innovative products that offer superior performance, efficiency and reliability, our team is equipped to deliver. Common stock is traded on the New York Stock Exchange under the ticker symbol MTOR.

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure:

- > Requirements gathering from the customer for the deliverables from the meetings.
- Prepare the check list for the systems migration and hardening.
- > Tune the systems as per the customer requirements.
- Implement the tools for the infrastructure systems monitoring and managing 24*7.
- > Documenting the process and help the team to learn the process to support platform.
- Migrating the systems and critical data from Data Centre to Cloud.
- > Building the systems using lift and shift migration techniques.
- Implementing Patch Management Tools for the cross-domain platforms for regular and periodic patch activities.
- Applying the bug fixes for SOX audit and on vulnerable systems.

- Defining and improving the Incident, Change and Problem processes and workflow for tickets.
- > Identifying the critical issues, prioritising them and providing fix to fall under SLA.
- Part of technical team building infra services NFS, SAMBA, FTP, vSFTP and Network printers.
- > Providing Knowledge to the new joiners, motivate them and make them work.
- > Provisioning storage to VM Instances and plan the growth of the storage for future.
- > Setting up infrastructure Manage Engine tools.
 - i) Operation Manage Engine Probe
 - ii) Operation Manage Engine Central
 - iii) Service Desk Plus MSP
 - iv) Patch Management Plus
 - v) Analytics for reports
- > Planning schedule and unscheduled activities for daily and weekend maintenance.
- Resolving business critical Sev 1 incidents issues.
- Supporting for internal and external audit from the infrastructure systems.
- Configuring the load balancers for the application services.
- > Shaping the VM Instances for the licensing and cost benefit.
- Co-ordinate, Plan and executing the Oracle Cloud (Vendor) maintenances.
- Creating Unix OS custom images for the infrastructure as per requirements.
- > Build the systems and implement hardening polices on them.
- ➤ Providing RCA root cause analysis for the business impacted systems.
- Span up the instances for High Availability.
- Migrating the data for cross region for over cloud operations.
- > Implementing Oracle Cloud Customized File service for the cloud operations.
- ➤ Implementing Oracle Cloud Customized EXACS services.
- Writing design decision documentation and is keen on implementing overall production best practices with a strong focus on security & encourage right Devops Workflows.
- > Participate in training, mentoring, and hiring the best.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY 3:

Worked as a Solaris Administrator in First Advantage Global Operating Centre Pvt Ltd. (A Symphony Technology Group Company) Bengaluru from Nov 2013 to Mar 2019, www.fadv.com

Description: (Background Screening and Verification)

First Advantage services in India cover over 1300 towns and cities, 6300 universities, all Government verification sources and employers across varied industries.

AWS AND RANCHER CLOUD:

- > Install, Configure, maintaining and troubleshooting on AWS EC2 instances.
- Snapshots and Provisioning S3 & Configure VPCs, ELBs, IAM
- Configure & Troubleshoot Storage Gateway, CloudFront
- Configure RDS, Auto Scaling groups
- Configure Cloud Watch& Route 53
- > Automation: Lambda, Spacewalk, Shell, Ansible and Jenkins.

- Support services before they go live through activities such as system design consulting, capacity planning and launch reviews.
- Maintain services once they are live by measuring and monitoring availability, latency, and overall system health.
- > Scale systems sustainably through mechanisms like automation and evolve systems by pushing for changes that improve reliability and velocity.

UNIX / LINUX:

- Install, Configure, maintaining and troubleshooting UNIX distribution out of Red Hat, Centos, OEL and Solaris operating systems.
- ▶ Played crucial role in building Data Center for Unix/Linux Environment.
- Migrating Unix/Linux Physical and Virtual machine.
- ▶ P2V and V2V Migration of Linux, Centos 5 and 6 on Virtual Environment.
- > Being at Data Centre workplace performing hardware maintenance and replacement.
- Managing and updating, web domains SSL/TLS Certificates of multiple Java based applications.
- ➤ Working on Internal and External Client Audits and business requirements.
- ▶ Hands on experience in Live Up-gradation of Solaris Servers and Zones.
- Working on Patch Management for Unix/Linux OS and Kernel Upgrade using Yum and Spacewalk.
- Firmware patching on different SUN hardware's platform V-Series, T-Series and M-Series.
- ➤ Working on Logical Volume Manager (LVM) and software/hardware RAID (0, 1, 5, 0+1, and 1+0) technologies.
- ➤ Install Configure and managing experience of Apache, Tomcat, and JBOSS.
- Deployment of. War,. jar, .ear on JBOSS 4.2 and JBOSS 7 and Web logic Environment.
- Configuring and managing the Monitoring Server and clients.
- > Configure and management of NIS, NTP, NFS, AUTOFS, DNS and SAMBA.
- > Hands on experienced on Security Tools like, Firewall, Iptables, TCP Wrapper, nmap.
- Configured NIC bonding in Linux Servers for fault tolerance.
- > Configured and installed Linux environments with Kickstart, PXE and NFS.
- Working with development & QA team for support their build, release, and basic test.
- Kernel compilation, up gradation, and kernel tuning for system optimum performance.
- Install Configure and managing Multipath and power path.
- Independent problem solving and a good team player with strong, interpersonal skills.
- > Working Experience on Oracle Virtual Machine and VMWARE Virtual Machine.
- Unix/Linux OS upgrades from 4.0/ 4.9 and 5/5.9 and 6/6.9
- Rebuild the servers from RHEL 4.x to RHEL 5.x and RHEL 6.x
- > Build the new physical and virtual servers as per the company standards.
- Verify the checklists for production ready and certify the servers for production.
- > Remediate the Security vulnerabilities at Application and Web layers.
- > Applying the patches for fixing the bugs at Application and Web layers.
- Experience on handing Sev 1 and Sev 2 critical issues.
- ► Hands on experience to perform the DR activities.
- > Experience with working in Production, Customer Test, UAT, and Development and Testing environments.

MIDDLEWARE TECHNOLOGIES:

Working on JBOSS, Web logic and Apache applications.

- > Working on Application JBOSS Deployment on Production Environment.
- > JBoss Application Tuning for the best performance.
- Adding New JBOSS Instances to the existing cluster.
- Working knowledge of Mod jk and Mod cluster.
- Performance monitoring as JBoss Application.
- Deployment on Web logic Applications.
- > Role based management on Web logic.
- Web logic tuning for the optimistic performance.
- ➤ Web logic cluster management with multiple instances.
- Web logic Applications integrations.
- Providing Security as the Web logic applications.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY 2:

Worked as a Technical Specialist in HCL Commnet System & Services Ltd [HCL Technologies Pvt Ltd] Bangalore from April 2011 to Nov 2013, www.hcl.com

Description of client (Energy Future Holdings)

Energy Future Holdings Corp. is a Dallas-based, privately held energy company with a portfolio of competitive and regulated energy companies. These businesses serve the high-growth Texas electricity market, which is one of the world's largest and among the nation's most successful competitive markets. EFH's competitive businesses consist primarily of **TXU Energy** and **LUMI NANT**. Its regulated operations consist of **ONCOR**.

WORK PROFILE & RESPONSIBLITIES:

- System administration, maintenance and monitoring various day-to-day operations.
- ➤ The support rendered is 24/7 in nature. The support is constantly monitored by SLA's which are though stringent but successfully met.
- Experience on File system and Disk management.
- ➤ Configure and marinating the Zones/containers in Solaris 10 servers and Linux machines.
- > Zone Migrations (V2V) and cloning
- ➤ Planning and Implementing change for Prod/Dev/Test environment to Live Upgradation Solaris OS and Migration in Unix/Linux machines on to Virtual Data Centre.
- ➤ Disk mirroring and RAID implementation using Solaris Volume Manager and VERITAS Volume Manager.
- ➤ Replacing the failed disk in VxVM & SVM and LVM Environments.
- > Configured and maintained VERITAS Volume Manager.
- Resizing the volumes and increasing file systems of zones (If under control of Vcs), VxVM & SVM and LVM Environments.
- > LVM, VERITAS File system and VERITAS Volume Manager used to configure the RAID 1 and RAID 5 Storage Systems.
- ➤ VERITAS Cluster Server bringing Service/Resource groups online/offline, switching service groups between cluster nodes & freezing the nodes.
- ➤ Clearing Service groups and troubleshooting on faulted service groups and determines issues with resolution.
- Responsible for handling the maintenance activities.
- Customer Support, Configuration, monitoring, troubleshooting of various Environments.
- ➤ Providing support to application teams while storage migration process.

- ➤ Planning and Implementing change for Prod/Dev/Test environment to OS/Firmware Up gradation (Patching) on various environments on different hardware platform for Vcs/ZFS/VxVM/SVM/LVM on Unix/Linux Operating System.
- ➤ Installs, Upgrades, Patches, Configuration, performance tuning on UNIX/Linux and system software & hardware.
- ➤ Planning and implementing change for Prod/Dev/Test environment to infrastructure build on SUN and DELL and HP Hardware and VMware ESX hosts (Solaris and Linux).
- > Working with Application teams for any issues related to Servers, software & hardware.
- Performed Custom Jump Start server to initiate installation of Solaris.
- ➤ Installing and configuring tolls like DB2 Client, Espresso and Commvault Simpana, BMC Patrol & Nagios (Monitoring tools).
- Troubleshooting and administration in ZFS and EXT2, EXT3 file systems.
- > Troubleshooting and administration in VERITAS Volume manager and Logical Volume Manager.
- > Troubleshooting and administration in Vcs 4.x & 5.x.
- ➤ Handling Day-to-Day Sev 1 and Sev 2 critical issues.
- > Experience to perform the DR activities.

VERITAS/Logical Volume Manager:

- Extensive working knowledge in VERITAS Volume Manager (LVM, VxVM, VxFS)& Clusters for Disk Management, Volume Management & increased disk availability.
- ➤ Implemented RAID levels Raid 0, Raid 1, Raid 0+1, and Raid 5 for Disk management. Upgrading normal file systems to RAID levels for growing size/redundancy requirements.
- ➤ Efficiency in installing, configuring, and implementing RAID Technologies using various tools like VERITAS volume manager, Solaris Volume manager and Logical Volume Manager.
- Expertise in VERITAS foundation suite, VxVM.

VERITAS Cluster:

- ➤ Hands on experience in Installing VERITAS Cluster on all the nodes.
- ➤ Hands on experience in VERITAS cluster (Fail over and Parallel cluster).
- ➤ Hands on experience in Creating/Adding Service group and Resources.
- > Building the Solaris zones/containers on Prod/Dev/Test and adding into the cluster member as a cluster node.
- Monitoring Service groups and Resources.
- ➤ Hands on experience in Configured NFS Service group in Cluster.
- ► Installing Cluster Agents and taking application into cluster.
- ➤ Performing cluster administration in C.L.I.

PROFESSIONL SUMMARY 1:

Worked as a Senior Specialist in HCL Commnet System & Services Ltd. Chennai from Nov 2010 to Apr 2011, www.hcl.com

Description of client (SKY ITALIA)

Tata Sky is media-based project, broad casting the movies, Games, political and ongoing latest news etc... Sky will be powered by a combination of Sun Fire E20K servers running

Ultra SPARC(R) IV+-based processors and Sun Fire Workgroup servers. The servers will run the Solaris (TM) 10 operating system with Sun N1(TM) System Manager to ensure maximum up-time, fault recovery and load management.

WORK PROFILE & RESPONSIBLITIES:

System administration, maintenance and monitoring various day-to-day operations.

- Experience on File system and Disk management.
- ➤ Package and Patch Management, Adding and Deleting Packages and patches according to the requirement.
- ➤ Configuring TCP/IP address, managing the SMF services.
- ➤ Backups of files and directories using utilities Ufsdump, gzip, gunzip, zip and compress.
- > Worked on services like FTP, SSH, SCP, Telnet, RSH.
- > Implemented NIS and NFS for administrative and project requirements.
- > Troubleshooting and configuring NFS servers, NIS servers and Auto mount environment in Unix/Linux.
- Scheduled tasks by using crontab & at jobs.
- Configure and managing the Zones in Solaris 10.
- ➤ Disk mirroring and RAID implementation using LVM, SVM and VxVM.
- > Replacing the failed disk in LVM, VxVM, SVM and LVM Environments.
- > Configured and maintained VERITAS Volume Manager.
- Resizing the volumes and increasing file system in VVR, VxVM, SVM and LVM Environments.
- > LVM and VERITAS file system configuration the RAID 1 and RAID 5 Storage Systems.
- ➤ Working experience with VERITAS Clustering.
- > VERITAS Cluster Server bringing Service/Resource groups online/offline, switching service groups between cluster nodes & freezing the nodes.
- > Responsible for handling the maintenance activities.
- Customer Support, Configuration, monitoring, troubleshooting of various Environments
- > Providing support to application teams while storage migration process.

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all above-mentioned information is in accordance with fact or truth up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibilities for the correctness of the above-mentioned.

Signature. (Chand Pasha)